<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Blue Bird Tales]]></title><description><![CDATA[LETS FILL THE BAG OF MEMORIES]]></description><link>https://gatsby-lam.vaporwavy.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 13:03:33 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Interrogation]]></title><description><![CDATA[Yesterday I was having a conversation with Samarth, my close friend, where I was just cursing the teacher who punished me for not…]]></description><link>https://gatsby-lam.vaporwavy.io/interrogation/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-lam.vaporwavy.io/interrogation/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I was having a conversation with Samarth, my close friend, where I was just cursing the teacher who punished me for not maintaining a proper notebook. Here, when I use the word “cursing” I want to suggest that I was putting a curse on her while cussing her. In exasperation I wanted to kick a stone near me but I restrained myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/bluebird/static/82494bbdd5fb078c33b1eeca643fb070/adfbf/int1.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
  
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin: 7vw 0; max-width: 905px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 72.37569060773481%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAAOABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFwABAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAUDBP/EABYBAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQCA//aAAwDAQACEAMQAAAB6JdKSW8w7L//xAAZEAACAwEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACAwABEiL/2gAIAQEAAQUCPN089MjV7ouDn//EABURAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAIQ/9oACAEDAQE/AXP/xAAWEQADAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEEBH/2gAIAQIBAT8BGi//xAAcEAABAwUAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABABARISIxQVH/2gAIAQEABj8CuiFQtnaI43//xAAbEAACAgMBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABEQAQIUFRYf/aAAgBAQABPyFxkDsyTAu0qBXxBSbV/9oADAMBAAIAAwAAABDHz//EABYRAAMAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABARgf/aAAgBAwEBPxB4P//EABkRAQACAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAEQIRExQf/aAAgBAgEBPxA7jeGuR//EABoQAQEAAwEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAERACExQWH/2gAIAQEAAT8QW5gFgini+4VwY5RZuYP3LPdiKXmzBU0gX3WFM//Z&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;picture&gt;
        &lt;source
          srcset=&quot;/bluebird/static/82494bbdd5fb078c33b1eeca643fb070/53e9f/int1.webp 340w,
/bluebird/static/82494bbdd5fb078c33b1eeca643fb070/0991f/int1.webp 680w,
/bluebird/static/82494bbdd5fb078c33b1eeca643fb070/1e0b6/int1.webp 905w&quot;
          sizes=&quot;(max-width: 905px) 100vw, 905px&quot;
          type=&quot;image/webp&quot;
        /&gt;
        &lt;source
          srcset=&quot;/bluebird/static/82494bbdd5fb078c33b1eeca643fb070/a0703/int1.jpg 340w,
/bluebird/static/82494bbdd5fb078c33b1eeca643fb070/5041d/int1.jpg 680w,
/bluebird/static/82494bbdd5fb078c33b1eeca643fb070/adfbf/int1.jpg 905w&quot;
          sizes=&quot;(max-width: 905px) 100vw, 905px&quot;
          type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot;
        /&gt;
        &lt;img
          class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
          style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
          src=&quot;/bluebird/static/82494bbdd5fb078c33b1eeca643fb070/adfbf/int1.jpg&quot;
          alt=&quot;vaporwave&quot;
          title=&quot;&quot;
          src=&quot;/bluebird/static/82494bbdd5fb078c33b1eeca643fb070/adfbf/int1.jpg&quot;
        /&gt;
      &lt;/picture&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I find myself lying in my bed staring blankly at the ceiling fan wondering about nothing in particular and yet I am regretful. When suddenly I hear a familiar voice asking me, “Why have you morphed yourself?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I replied after deriving out whose voice it was, “I thought that it was cool. But now that I think of it, I know it’s a lame answer, as lame as the reason behind every terrorist attack.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He, continuing with his interrogation, asked me another question “Why did you kill him? Why?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To which I further inquired “Who are you talking about? Shashwat?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He replied with a sly smile on his face “You know who I am talking about. No one knows better than you and you cannot lie to me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interrogation was weighing down heavily on me and I could feel the walls of truth closing in. “Gloomy winds hitting my eyes condensing the vapors inviting drops of water and salt”, these words from a famous poem by an unknown poet resonated with my inner turmoil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My eyes brimmed with tears and my voice croaked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I said, trying to explain myself, “It all happened with the flow of events in my life. The waves of occurrence sometimes made me soar high and sometimes abandoned me in the crests of oblivion.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He replied in a calm voice, “Allow these tears to flow and let this moment be a reflection of your true self. Let me take you on a journey into our past and show you who you were. When you were 10-years old you were different, you did not have any pretensions and you were courteous. You respected everyone’s thought, you gave me some thought before you did anything, and I was your friend. Let me remind you who you were. It was the month of March and the school had reopened after long holidays you were both excited and stressed; excited because you were going to meet new friends and stressed because you were going to miss your old classmates. But you never expressed it to anyone. Entered into the classroom whistling, the bag slung across one shoulder and most importantly spikes (hairstyle).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First period had just begun; you were sitting on the first bench looking around the class searching for someone to chat with when suddenly you saw a teacher walking down the corridor with a cast on her left hand and a bag full of a bulk of stuff on her right. Her face revealed a story of a painful incident that left a brutal scar in its wake. You were scared not because of her burned face but because of the stories that were filled in your mind by your classmates of her being an extremely strict teacher. She entered the classroom and all the boys stood up and wished her in a ringing voice, “good morning ma’am”, as if they were asked to sing a song. She asked you all to sit, and said, “Hello students, my name is Mrs Reena Majumdar and I am your new class teacher. I will be teaching you Social Studies and English, although my main subjects are Maths and Science.” She asked everyone to introduce themselves, and when it was your turn, you replied in a sassy manner, “Good morning, ma’am, my name is Shashwat Dubey”. She smiled and replied with a friendly quip, “Good morning, Panditji”. Everyone started laughing including you; if it was the Shashwat of today he would have gotten irritated. Rumors about her being strict proved to be baseless gossip. She was not like any other teacher; she was a mentor and a caring person. In hindsight she was just like a second mother to you. She was such a teacher with whom every student could share their problems even in front of whole class as she had the ability to create an aura of warm comfort which helped the students to trust her with their most intimate issues. She was the one who always had faith in you. Don’t you remember when she stood up for you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought for a while and replied, “Yes I do remember, it was during the preparatory week of annual function and teachers of lower classes were busy in the rehearsals so a few 5th class students were sent over for monitoring them. I and Mutahir were also selected. We were sent to the 2nd grade, section B, which was on the first floor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we entered, we saw that the puckish children were standing on the desks and creating a ruckus. Mutahir made an unsuccessful try to calm them; suddenly, enraged, I screamed, “SHUT UP!” bringing everyone to a standstill, terrified. I tried to behave as if I am a strict senior but I could not realize when monitoring the class turned into bulling. Whenever I heard a murmuring sound, I used to beat the boys with a hard-wooden scale on their forearms. A boy among st them, who was a frail kid, stood up from his seat and started a mutiny against me saying, “No one gave you the right to hit us”. I took the scale and whacked him with annoyance visible on my face. He started sobbing hysterically in pain. Next day a letter came to ma’am’s desk which made her ask me in infuriation, “Shashwat can you explain to me what actually happened yesterday?” I solved the mystery in the very first moment when she said “yesterday”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to save myself I inquired feigning innocence, “Ma’am what?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She smiled in disgust and said, “Do you actually don’t know what happened?! Come and meet me at the staircase after the class”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On my way to the stair case I was trying to solve the riddle that who might have snitched about me?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of nowhere, ma’am grabbed my collar and said, “I have your suspension letter in my hand.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My eyes became wider in shock and I was not able to utter a single word.    Ma’am said, “I can help you out with this problem but why should I do it? Should I help you so that you can repeat this blunder?”                                                                                                                                                                        My eyes brimmed with tears and I replied, “Ma’am, I’ll never bully anyone ever again.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her face gave away nothing and she continued with her scrutiny. She inquired once again, “Is it a promise?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I replied, strong willed, “Yes ma’am, I promise!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later that day, I was invited to the Principal’s office unceremoniously. The cool breeze from the air-conditioner hits my face, however the aura inside was anything but calm. The kid and his annoyed parents leapt at me with all their allegations and misgivings. They persuaded the Principal, with all their might, to take strict action against me. After listening to them for a while it suddenly dawned on me that I had been summoned to receive my suspension letter and no more. Then ma’am stood up from her seat and said to the Principal that she wanted to talk to the kid’s parents.  She took a stand for me and requested them to take the complaint. I was downcast in my own eyes that day because an upstanding lady was forced to beg for me. In the end they understood and took the complaint back. One more thing happened that day, it transformed me from a bully to an empathetic person.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; My soul doesn’t need my permission before splashing thoughts that drift me into a spiral. Thoughts are his way of speaking. So, he started narrating to me a story -“It was your last day in 5th grade and everyone was feeling emotional because of the bond that was shared by all. Reena ma’am entered the classroom and everyone stood up from their seats and chanted in a unison, “Good morning, ma’am”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She asked everyone to sit and then said, “Good morning students, how are you all? Today I am going to reveal a mystery.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Out of curiosity Samarth inquired, “What type of mystery, ma’am?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; She looked at him and replied, in a conspiratorial tone, “A mystery you all were wondering about since day one, the reason behind the scars on my face. Since you all share your intimate issues with me, I also want to share something intimate to me. One day while I was returning back home on my Kinetic Honda, the fuel pipe started leaking petrol and suddenly a flame erupted out of the engine and my saree was caught on fire. I lost balance and fell in the middle of road. The flame swiftly travelled through the fabric of my saree like a serpent and in no time I was engulfed in a fears fire. My skin had started to blister but the people in the vicinity kept staring at me shamelessly with no intention to help. My clothes were burned off and I was running in excruciating pain; some teachers came rushing towards me from a school nearby and covered me with blanket to extinguish the fire. Even in that pain I was thinking why were they just staring?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The students sat in stunned silence. Reena ma’am continued, “As a teacher in a boy’s school it’s my duty to teach you that one should never ever keep back in helping someone and should never disrespect a woman.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My soul was now intently looking at me. I told him, “Some thoughts came to my mind when she was narrating the story that told me that there is more to this story than meets the eye. If circumstances prove to be harsh, one should retain their identity. Reena ma’am had always been strong and fearless. I want to meet her once again.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My soul questioned, “Is that Shashwat still alive, which ma’am had known?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a curious Greek physicist Archimedes came up with his own principle which states that an up thrust or buoyant force allows an immersed object to float in a fluid. Here, my mind is floating in confusion, my will to meet ma’am is acting as the buoyant force but the weight of my guilt and hesitation is far heavier. I am sinking deeper and deeper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly a voice fills my ears, “Get up, Shashwat! It’s 7 AM, bus will be arriving any moment, get up, Shashwat!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel a hand shaking me and I see my mom screaming, because I’m getting late for my school, as usual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow, I made myself reach school on time. Everything is going well but my soul is disturbing me during the class. I want to lodge a complaint about him but if I do so I’m certain that the teacher will refer me to a psychiatrist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot is happening around me but I’m not aware. My friends start to call me,  ´present body absent mind’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The day at school comes to an end. An unexperienced anxiety grows within me when I see Reena ma’am passing through the main gate. I run towards her without worrying about any hesitation I might have had and when I came close to her, I said, breathlessly, “Good morning, ma’am.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She replied, “Its afternoon, Pandit ji. How are you?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I said with a sly smile on my face, “Yes ma’am, good afternoon, I’m fine, now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;                                                            -Shashwat D.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[A Bond]]></title><description><![CDATA[When I was 10 years old, I joined a football club. I was not enthusiastic about football but I went to save myself from getting bored at…]]></description><link>https://gatsby-lam.vaporwavy.io/bond/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-lam.vaporwavy.io/bond/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;When I was 10 years old, I joined a football club. I was not enthusiastic about football but I went to save myself from getting bored at home. Those days I used to live in a colony where most of the people were Muslims; there were approximately 30-40 children of my age group in my colony. There was a boy called  Junaid who used to bring his bat and ball. His family members were narrow minded and so was he. Junaid   never allowed me to play with him . He  stopped me from using  his bat and ball and that’s why I could not play with my colony friends .One day, during Ramzan, after running for half an hour our coach asked us to rest for ten minutes. That time I came to know that I had forgotten to bring my water bottle. So instead of just asking my colleagues to give me some water to drink, I went to them and I said, “Hey, my name is Altaf and I am fasting due to Ramzan but now I can not control my thirst. So, can I get some water to drink? I thought they would be kinder towards me and I’ll get special treatment. What I thought was accurate since all of them offered me to share their water. But one boy was continuously staring at me; that boy‘s name was Ramanadhan Sastry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day our coach organised a match between one team lead by Arjun and the other team by Ramanadhan. My good friend Parth was on Ramnaadha’s team , so I asked Ramandhan to take me in his team too but he refused saying that they were having sufficient players. After that Parth went to him asking why he lied even though they needed me in their team. Ramanadhan’s reply was something that made me speechless and drove me into a state of melancholy.  He told Parth that he is a Muslim and so how can he sit with me , play with me and be my teammate? He said that if he allows me to play with them I would be the main reason for their disunity. Junaid’s and Ramanadhan’s ideas were so similar but they both belonged to different communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; One day while I was sitting in my balcony staring at Junaid and his friends playing cricket, Junaid hit the ball with all his strength and the ball unfortunately strukes the bonnet of ex : major Basheer Mohamad’s car and entered his house and injures his goat which he had brought for the night’s feast . What happened next was a devastating experience for Junaid as the infuriated goat started running behind him. I ran downstairs got on my cycle and rode behind the goat and charged it with my whole strength . Fortunately or unfortunately, i don’t know , I lost control and fell on the harmless goat; it could not handle my weight and it collapsed. And in the confusion I protected Junaid from this frail beast’s horns.
After that something happened that I never expected, Junaid hugged me tightly and said, “thank you, bhaijaan”. His words inspired an emotion of joy within me. After that day Junaid became one of my best friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ramanadhan and his seven-year old sister used to go back home from the same route which I took. One day while we were going back home, I saw them walking in front of me. I was wondering what would happen if the bottle in his sister’s hand, which she was juggling, fell on her own feet when suddenly two men on a bike wearing helmets came to a halt near Ramanadhan. They were enquiring about an address and all of a sudden the man on the backseat (the pillion rider) clutched his sister from his biceps and started to ride away; I picked up a stone from the ground and threw it with sheer will; that stone hit the rider on his hand and they lost the balance. The bike swerved and fell to the ground with a shrilling sound. A group of people came running from one side of the road while I ran from the other. I asked his sister, “are you okay?” to which she replied, “I’m fine now, thank you”. Ramnadhan hugged me tightly saying, “thank you, bhai”. His emotions moved me and brought tears to my eyes and a smile to my face. And this was the starting point of an unbreakable bond of love between us.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Parrot Outside The Cage]]></title><description><![CDATA[One early morning my friend Deendayal and I  were sitting under a mango tree in a dense forest. The wind was blowing , caressing me like my…]]></description><link>https://gatsby-lam.vaporwavy.io/its-all-blue/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gatsby-lam.vaporwavy.io/its-all-blue/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;One early morning my friend Deendayal and I  were sitting under a mango tree in a dense forest. The wind was blowing , caressing me like my  mother’s gentle pat making me forget about my homework, timetable, bullies, insults, griefs, worries, and almost everything. Trees were waving their branches in the concert of birds and flowers were opening up their bloom shops,  welcoming  pollinators for a feast. The God’s sun walks the sky with his heavenly guards and distributes light to its disciples. And like this dawn arrives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deendayal was pleased with the soothing breeze of happiness floating over the chirping of birds. The beauty of nature leads him to praise nature ‘Is it possible  to capture all this in a box?, I asked out of fascination. ‘In that case will nature’s nature be real?’ he replied, looking up into the sky. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His words made me travel through a deep well of thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said pointing towards a parrot sitting on a guava tree,’Look at that parrot!There are certain reasons for which God has created it the way it is.’ I was listening to him attentively. ‘There are reasons behind its color, hookbill beak and its feather’.I said to him, ‘I didn’t get your point’ He explained further,’I’m trying to convey that the parrot’s  color helps it camouflage with  its environment hiding from its predators, his hookbill shaped beak helps it in climbing trees and  crushing fruits. Its feathers help it in maintaining its body temperature. These features of the parrots would lose its importance in that box. No matter how luxurious that enclosure be; it will always remain a prison for the creature.’ His words were blowing like a wind opening the window of my mind , through the window scattered the light of thoughts waking me up from the illusion of happiness. ‘God is an artist!’ he said in a  thoughtful tone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-link&quot;
    href=&quot;/bluebird/static/65225205d7af61faee3d3c89ea243227/8dedd/parrot.jpg&quot;
    style=&quot;display: block&quot;
    target=&quot;_blank&quot;
    rel=&quot;noopener&quot;
  &gt;
  
  &lt;span
    class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-wrapper&quot;
    style=&quot;position: relative; display: block; margin: 7vw 0; max-width: 1360px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot;
  &gt;
    &lt;span
      class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-background-image&quot;
      style=&quot;padding-bottom: 56.25%; position: relative; bottom: 0; left: 0; background-image: url(&apos;data:image/jpeg;base64,/9j/2wBDABALDA4MChAODQ4SERATGCgaGBYWGDEjJR0oOjM9PDkzODdASFxOQERXRTc4UG1RV19iZ2hnPk1xeXBkeFxlZ2P/2wBDARESEhgVGC8aGi9jQjhCY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2NjY2P/wgARCAALABQDASIAAhEBAxEB/8QAFwABAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAABA//EABYBAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAIAAf/aAAwDAQACEAMQAAABDxbmQ5kh/8QAGxABAAICAwAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQACAxESEyH/2gAIAQEAAQUC69xgCPiY6TFU4f/EABURAQEAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABAS/9oACAEDAQE/AZP/xAAVEQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQEv/aAAgBAgEBPwGj/8QAGhAAAQUBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAECESExgf/aAAgBAQAGPwKZROmmFDqMP//EABoQAAMBAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABIRExYYH/2gAIAQEAAT8hcEYCrJpv3RQ7+lw1RHKTp//aAAwDAQACAAMAAAAQk9//xAAWEQADAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAQITH/2gAIAQMBAT8QeD//xAAWEQEBAQAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAABACH/2gAIAQIBAT8QAYwN/8QAGhABAQEBAQEBAAAAAAAAAAAAAREhADFhsf/aAAgBAQABPxACGJcV+zj+oSRXIWmiyVv3m4hHKX95jrIU1zgyhr07/9k=&apos;); background-size: cover; display: block;&quot;
    &gt;
      &lt;picture&gt;
        &lt;source
          srcset=&quot;/bluebird/static/65225205d7af61faee3d3c89ea243227/53e9f/parrot.webp 340w,
/bluebird/static/65225205d7af61faee3d3c89ea243227/0991f/parrot.webp 680w,
/bluebird/static/65225205d7af61faee3d3c89ea243227/9d77c/parrot.webp 1360w,
/bluebird/static/65225205d7af61faee3d3c89ea243227/27063/parrot.webp 2040w,
/bluebird/static/65225205d7af61faee3d3c89ea243227/4342c/parrot.webp 2400w&quot;
          sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1360px) 100vw, 1360px&quot;
          type=&quot;image/webp&quot;
        /&gt;
        &lt;source
          srcset=&quot;/bluebird/static/65225205d7af61faee3d3c89ea243227/a0703/parrot.jpg 340w,
/bluebird/static/65225205d7af61faee3d3c89ea243227/5041d/parrot.jpg 680w,
/bluebird/static/65225205d7af61faee3d3c89ea243227/fe1b8/parrot.jpg 1360w,
/bluebird/static/65225205d7af61faee3d3c89ea243227/25fce/parrot.jpg 2040w,
/bluebird/static/65225205d7af61faee3d3c89ea243227/8dedd/parrot.jpg 2400w&quot;
          sizes=&quot;(max-width: 1360px) 100vw, 1360px&quot;
          type=&quot;image/jpeg&quot;
        /&gt;
        &lt;img
          class=&quot;gatsby-resp-image-image&quot;
          style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%; margin: 0; vertical-align: middle; position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; box-shadow: inset 0px 0px 0px 400px white;&quot;
          src=&quot;/bluebird/static/65225205d7af61faee3d3c89ea243227/fe1b8/parrot.jpg&quot;
          alt=&quot;b&quot;
          title=&quot;&quot;
          src=&quot;/bluebird/static/65225205d7af61faee3d3c89ea243227/fe1b8/parrot.jpg&quot;
        /&gt;
      &lt;/picture&gt;
      &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;
  
  &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Everyone has its own role in this world. The almighty creator has connected everyone to a chain of nature, and if one connected to that chain trembles others too would lose their balance.’What are you talking about?’I enquired. ‘I’m trying  to tell you that everyone is interdependent in nature. Like this parrot gets fruits to eat from the forest and in return it disperses the seeds all over the jungle and adds manure to the soil; It is the gardener of this huge forest. It also leaves some morsels for ants in its wake and makes holes in the fruits so that insects like flies or honeybees, which cannot pierce the fruit skin by themselves can have it. When they are kept in a cage where they have sufficient food, water and the love of its master, still it cannot be satisfied with its life. The parrot will be removed from this chain but will always be behind  bars. They are incomplete without the forest like an awesome beat without lyrics.’, he elaborated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pushed  into a confounding reverie by his words. I gave a gentle pat on his shoulder and we both sat in the silence of understanding for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The morning had now evolved into afternoon and the light of thoughts had now turned into the light of realization. We rode back to our homes swerving through the city hustling for money and fame with a hope that it will bring peace in their lives. Unaware of the fact that you don’t always have to achieve happiness. Life has its own beauty. Why aren’t  we exploring that? Why are we battling to own happiness? God is an artist and only an artist could read the stories that he weaves.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>